<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smashing Keys Daily</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://hatbkwds.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hatbkwds.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 17:23:21 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 17:23:21 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unity and Virtual Reality</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Unity I am a complete beginner having only started working with
it for the past month and having no prior experience with game programming. I will
start by saying it is Awesome! I don’t know how people used to make video games
before game engines like Unity and UnReal and hopefully that isn’t something that
drives me insane as to where I research into building my own game engine when
these super powerful easy to use engines already exist and are free to use. So far
I have started working through the Unity tutorials and I’ve already learned so much.
I am planning on running through all of the tutorials before making my own game
so that I will have a great grasp as to how everything works, well and because
an idea for a game has yet to find it’s way into my mind that is super ambitious.
&lt;br /&gt;
Today I went to a Unity meet up where virtual reality was being discussed. Having
read about it online but yet to actually experience it, not being made of $, being
able to see what resources for developing on the different units was really eye
opening. Once I get around to upgrading my desktop the next to do item will be
saving up for either the Oculus or HTC Vive. Being around professional game openers
has swayed me slightly into focusing solely on being a game developer knowing that
the money and job security may not be the best in the field. What is more fun than
creating something so that others can have fun?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatbkwds.github.io//unity/virtual/reality/vr/2016/01/13/unity-and-virtual-reality.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatbkwds.github.io//unity/virtual/reality/vr/2016/01/13/unity-and-virtual-reality.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Unity</category>
        
        <category>Virtual</category>
        
        <category>Reality</category>
        
        <category>VR</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SVG Files</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started when I wanted to move the RSS Feed from the footer to the header.
I figured since that sounded like an easy task to do it would take maybe 5-10
minutes tops. Boy was I wrong! I worked on it for a good hour trying to figure
out not just what a .svg file was but how to make one and then how to fix them.
I know all about .gif, .png, .jpg, .ai, but now you want to throw .svg into the
mix… After some good all internet searching I managed to find that Illustrator
could convert an image into a svg file. I was mentally ecstatic thinking how easy
it would be so I open Illustrator, create a logo for the RSS feed, save the file,
and then create the html file and upload it to the site. I was just about to smile
and call it a success when I realized the logo was just a gray logo. Well, after
zooming in I realized my logo was there but just a black outline over a gray circle
making it invisible. After some time I realized the issue was that in Illustrator
I did not have a transparent background. Easy fix, or so I thought. If you zoom
in to the logo now, or at least until I figure out how to change it, you will
notice that there is some gray outline by each arc. After looking up how to fix
it and coming across no solution and knowing little about svg files I called it
a night and left the logo as is. I will come back to try to understand how you
work one day svg!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatbkwds.github.io//jekyll/svg/illustrator/gray/2016/01/11/svg-files.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatbkwds.github.io//jekyll/svg/illustrator/gray/2016/01/11/svg-files.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>svg</category>
        
        <category>illustrator</category>
        
        <category>gray</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll Novice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They say the third time is the charm and since this is now the third time I am
resurrecting my personal blog I am hoping this is also the last time I do so
from scratch (No, I don’t mean I used MIT’s Scratch language). What a learning
experience it was to start with Jekyll having only dabbed into web development
since the majority of my time is spent in the software world. It is quite
frustrating to write a css file or html file to have it just up and disappear
once you run the server. If only I had read &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;the manual&lt;/a&gt; before
trying to just jump straight into the coding (Sigh). Anyway, after doing so and
figuring out how the markdown language and sass works it was eye opening! The
overall look of the site will definitely be improved over time but since I am
 going to go ahead and do all the coding myself without the help of templates
 that will take some time. Going to go back to Python and Unity for now so stay
 tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 05:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hatbkwds.github.io//jekyll/sass/markdown/md/scss/2016/01/10/jekyll-novice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hatbkwds.github.io//jekyll/sass/markdown/md/scss/2016/01/10/jekyll-novice.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>sass</category>
        
        <category>markdown</category>
        
        <category>md</category>
        
        <category>scss</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
